

Product Management Leader Mobile, Customer Obsession, Data

CONTACT

ABOUT ME

971-258-4060 Rahul.hi@gmail.com 8515 Brodie Ln, Austin, Texas 78745 Entrepreneurial self-starter leader with 8-plus years of work experience and great passion for building consumer internet products. Core expertise in maintaining laser focus on customer, while being ROI and technology driven. An intuitive strategist, and long term planner with a unique perspective on market challenges and upcoming technologies.

EDUCATION

EXPERIENCE

University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign (UIUC)

M.S. Engineering **DEC 2012**

University of Illinois at Urbana Champaign (UIUC)

College of Business Certificate of Excellence, Sustainable Management & Technology, MAY 2012

Indian Institute of Technology Roorkee

B.S. Engineering **MAY 2009**

(IIT Roorkee)

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Agile Software Development

Kanban, Scrum, SAFe, etc.

Analytics Pro Google Analytics, Omniture Sitecatalyst, Mix Panel,

Adobe Analytics

2017 – Present Amazon, Austin – TX

Senior Product Manager, Mobile App – Amazon Business

- Launched B2B buying experience in the amazon shopping app to allow businesses to buy in bulk while receiving quantity discounts and other business benefits generating \$50M+ in monthly revenue.
- Launched a curated buying experience in amazon shopping app by highlighting products in the search results page that b2b customers prefer to buy. Generated 45% incremental revenue from the curation feature.

RetailMeNot Inc., Austin – TX

2014 - 2017

Senior Product Manager, Mobile App & Location Services

- Lead a cross functional team of Engineers, Designers, BA, Operations, Finance and Marketing to build Geo-targeting capabilities for retailers generating over \$600K in sales.
- Developed an attribution model by leveraging location signal to measure in-store visits. Successfully launched a brand new mobile attribution report to 100+ retailers driving \$10M+ revenue in sales
- Built "app-to-app linking" product to drive acquisition and re-engagement for retailers while delivering better UX within mobile app ecosystem.
- Implemented advanced location capabilities in the app (Gimbal & Placer SDK) to deliver contextually relevant user experience while enabling team to improve personalization and targeting algorithms.
- Rapidly tested new algorithms (Heuristic & Machine Learning) to rank offers on landing pages and deployed them to drive incremental \$1MM annualized revenue.
- Defined new experiments by collaborating with design team to create experiences, managing engineering effort to launch tests and working with BA to lead analysis & integrate results.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

Usability Testing Fanatic

UserTesting.com, InVision, UserZoom, Apptentive, etc.

Product Management Software Ace

Confluence, Jira, ProdPad

Natural Collaborator

Zepline, Salesforce, Sharepoint, Quip

Technical Languages & Tools

C, C++, Java, Visual Basic SQL, R, Teradata SQL Assistant

DIVERSIFIED LEARNING

John Deere

Project on agricultural value chain
Product development process
Product prototype
Comprehensive business plan

Illinois Green Business Association

Community learning Green business initiative

OTCR Consulting

Market Research – Media Industry Business expansion plan

Enablon Consulting

Implemented SaaS solutions

ASSOCIATIONS

Toastmasters Club, VP Public Relations Agile Austin Product Austin

EXPERIENCE

Latentview Analytics, San Jose – CA Senior Product Analyst, Data Analytics

2013 - 2014

- Redesigned customer loyalty & rewards program for a major ecommerce client
 - o Directly impacting 5MM buyers across the US
- Optimized email campaign and onsite marketing by collaborating with CRM and Loyalty analytics team
 - o Estimated the worth of a specific site feature to be \$100MM by running a 2 month pilot project
 - o Impact Increment in revenue by \$8MM
- Worked with Trust Analytics team to manage global marketplaces and improved buyer experience
 - o Reduced bad buyer experience rate by 95 basis points

ZS Associates, New Delhi - India

2010 - 2011

General Analytics Associate, Sales & Marketing Strategy

- Worked with \$16B pharmaceutical client to create a sales forecasting model for their business
 - Forecasted 10 years of sales with a projected growth rate of 4% YoY to increase revenue from \$16B to \$22B
 - o Enabled faster and consolidated reporting of their sales in 20 countries
- Owned end-to-end responsibility for creating and supporting analytic solutions and processes to address specific client questions, especially related to sales and marketing operations.

Deloitte Consulting, Mumbai – India

2009 - 2010

Business Technology Analyst, Systems Integration

- Provided IT consulting in Technology, Media and Telecommunication sector.
- Collaborated with clients and researched their users to gain deeper understanding of the business requirements.
- Worked in a team of eight members and analyzed business requirements and further translated them into technical requirements by creating functional breakdown structures.
- Provided knowledge transfer sessions of the design, data and defects, to the client representatives using Excel reports prepared during user acceptance testing (UAT).

CROSS-FUCTIONAL MIX

